beamng.com 2019-12-28

# Privacy Policy - BeamNG

## Data Privacy Policy of BeamNG

### 1 Our commitment to privacy

Thank you very much for your interest in our website, www.beamng.com (hereinafter the "Website"). This Website is operated by BeamNG GmbH, Fahrenheitstraße 1, 28359 Bremen (hereinafter referred to as ‘BeamNG’ or ‘we’/’us’). It offers you as the user (hereinafter referred to as ‘User’ or ‘you’) the opportunity to get an idea of our games, make requests, and register to receive materials. 

Your privacy is important to us. In what follows, we will provide you with information about how we use your personal data when you visit our Website and which rights you have with respect to our use of your personal data. Any consent you grant may be withdrawn at any time with future effect. If you have any questions about our use of your personal data, please contact us (at the e-mail address shown in Section 10 below). To make this privacy policy easy to find, we make it available on our homepage and at every point where personally identifiable information may be requested. 

### 2 Data we collect and the way we use the data

2.1 Any User is free to visit our Website without having to register. 

2.2 Every time a User visits the Website or opens a file the following data will be stored in a log file: Internet protocol, shortened IP address, page from which the file was accessed, date, time, browser type and operating system, the pages visited by the User, volume of data transferred, access status (file transmitted, file not found, etc.). 

These data are used to generate pseudonymized statistics which help us analyse the use of our website, correct errors and improve our services. The details of the web analysis using pseudonymous data and the options of users to object to (or prevent) such an analysis at any time are set forth in Section 9. 

2.3 Apart from that we only collect and use personal data the User discloses during visits to the Website, for instance when registering as User, placing an order or using the Website contact form to make an enquiry. The User’s personal data are collected, used and stored for the purpose of executing a contract. Personal data are information which contain details of your personal or material circumstances, such as your name, address, e-mail address and date of birth. 

2.4 The types of personal information collected for registration as a User are name or nickname, email address. In addition any profile information that the User entered while visiting our Website is collected and stored. 

2.5 Personal data are treated as strictly confidential and are not divulged to third parties without the User’s consent unless this is necessary for the purpose of executing orders, settling payments, processing enquiries or customer care. The data may also be disclosed if necessary to protect other users or if its disclosure is required by law. 

2.6 In case a registered User enters information or statements in the public Forum (‘Forum’), he knows and agrees that these statements and information are published within the public Forum of BeamNG. 

2.7 Furthermore, contractual and utilization data are collected, processed and used by BeamNG pursuant to Sections 14 & 15 of the German Telemedia Act (Telemediengesetz - TMG) and Section 28 of the German Data Protection Act (Bundesdatenschutzgesetz - BDSG). 

### 3 Your Consent in data exchange between the Game and the Server

In order to offer our scoring system to you we will have to make a transfer of data and information of the Game from your display device to our BeamNG servers. You will be informed at the beginning of using the Game about this and the necessity of the data transfer in order to use some features of the Game and will be asked for your consent. You may revoke the consent to use the information/data at any time by changing the "Online Features" in the Game settings. 

### 4 Our commitment to data security

To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of information, we have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online. Nonetheless, making available your personal data, whether in person, by telephone or online, is always associated with certain risks, and no technical system is completely immune to manipulation or sabotage. 

### 5 Our commitment to children's privacy

Protecting the privacy of the very young is especially important. For that reason, we never collect or maintain information at our website from those we actually know are under 13, and no part of our website is structured to attract anyone under 13. 

### 6 How you can access or correct your information

6.1 You can access all your personally identifiable information that we collect online and maintain by acessing your forum profile. 

6.2 You can correct factual errors in your personally identifiable information by sending us a request that credibly shows error. 

6.3 To protect your privacy and security, we will also take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting access or making corrections. 

### 7 How we process and delete data

7.1 We may, on our own initiative or at your request, supplement, correct or delete any incomplete, erroneous or outdated data stored in connection with the operation of the Website. 

7.2 We will delete data in compliance with applicable law promptly upon User’s request, unless we are required to keep your data on file under applicable law. 

### 8 Cookies

We use so-called "cookies" on our Website, i.e., text files that are stored on your display device and that can be used to collect certain user-specific settings and technical information. This allows us to improve your experience when using the Website. Using cookies is standard practice on many websites. Cookies are stored on your display device, not on our Website. 

Our forum software uses a number of different cookies for working correctly: 

  * bb_userid = Logged in User's ID
  * bb_password = MD5 hash of the logged in user's password.
  * bb_lastvisit = timestamp of your last visit.
  * bb_lastactivity = timestamp of your last activity.
  * bb_skipmobilestyle = User doesn't want the mobile style.
  * bb_userstyleid = Style ID chosen from footer.
  * bb_sessionhash = Users current session hash.
  * bb_cpsessionhach = Moderator or Admin CP login session.
  * bb_markread = List of threads the user has read this session if using Cookie-Based Read Marking
  * vbulletin_collapse = what elements the user has collapsed.
  * vbulletin_sidebar_collapse = Whether or not the forum sidebar is collapsed
  * editor_height = Height of the Editor if you resize it.

Users will be informed that cookies are used when they first use the Website. 

Opt-out, objection rights 

If you do not wish cookies to be stored on your display device, wish to delete stored cookies, or wish to be notified when cookies are stored, you can select the appropriate settings in your browser, e.g., by selecting the browser setting "accept no cookies". You will find step-by-step instructions in the help menu of your browser. If you use the Website without choosing appropriate settings in your browser, you thereby consent to the use of cookies as described in this Privacy Policy. 

### 9 Piwik

Additionally, we use Piwik Web Analytics for statistics. Piwik uses cookies, which are stored on your display device and allow for analysis of your use of the Website. The information collected by analyzing the use of our Website is stored on our own servers in Germany and is analyzed in-house only. The IP address is anonymized immediately after processing and prior to storage, so that users of the Website cannot be identified. Data collected via Piwik are used only for statistically analyzing website traffic to improve our Website and are not merged with personal data, either at the time data are collected or at any time thereafter. Data are not transferred to third parties. 

Opt-out, objection rights You may object to Piwik analysis of your personal data. There are different ways of doing so: For example, you can prevent cookies from being stored on your terminal device by selecting the appropriate settings in your browser software. If you wish to prevent an analysis of your online behavior in general, you can activate the "Do Not Track" option of current web browsers in your browser. 

In addition, you can object to and prevent Piwik analysis of your personal data by clicking on the link below: [http://piwik.beamng.com/index.php?module=CoreAdminHome&action=optOut&language=en](http://piwik.beamng.com/index.php?module=CoreAdminHome&action=optOut&language=en) Your visits to the Website will then no longer be tracked by Piwik. 

Note that if you remove cookies that have been stored in your browser, the Piwik deactivation cookie of this Website likewise will be deleted. The Piwik deactivation cookie is valid only for the specific terminal device on which it is stored. If you use a different display device, you will have to object to Piwik analysis of your personal data once again. 

By using the Website without objection you agree that your personal data may be processed in the manner and for the purpose described above. 

### 10 How to contact us

You may contact us at any time, if you want your profile and related personal data to be corrected, blocked or deleted, or if you wish to revoke consent to our use of your e-mail address for purposes of sending you our newsletter. Moreover, we will at any time disclose to you which data are stored, what the origin of the data is, who the recipient of the data is, and the purpose for which data are stored. If you have any questions concerning data protection, please contact us at: 

  * Website: <http://www.beamng.com/contactus>
  * E-Mail: support@beamng.com
  * Phone: +49 421 40 8 94 3 94

  * Contact:

    Thomas Fischer
    BeamNG GmbH
    Fahrenheitstr. 1
    28359 Bremen
    Germany
